A Guide to the Helen Norris Cummings Papers, 1865-1949
Alexandria Library, Local History/Special Collections
Alexandria Library, Local History/Special Collections
Helen Norris Cummings Papers 1865-1949
Alexandria Library, Local History/Special Collections
72
This collection consists of the research materials of Helen Norris Cummings, founder of the Cameron Club, member of the Federation of Women's Club, and local historian.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Esther Green Estate, 1986.
Biographical/Historical Information
Helen Norris Cummings, daughter of Norris Cummings (1834-1904) and Emma Ricketts Cummings (d. 1930), resided in Alexandria from about 1894 until 1949, the time of her death. The family came from Philadelphia, where Norris had been involved in "William Cummings and Son," his family's international shipping business. Helen was active in community affairs. In 1894 she founded the Cameron Club, a member of the Federation of Women's Clubs. (See Cameron Club Collection). She also held various positions in the Virginia Federation of Women's Clubs.
Scope and Content
The correspondence spans the period from 1870 to 1943. Most of the pre-1905 letters deal with genealogy, and the majority of these are addressed to Emma, Helen's mother. Approximately half of the 1905 to 1920 letters are also Emma's. Many of Helen's letters deal with political issues, such as immigration and radicalism. Box 72E Folder 4 contains numerous letters from congressmen. These appear to be responses to her comments on immigration. Among the agencies from which she received letters are the National Republic, The Movement Against Socialism in the Church, and the Industrial Defense Association.
The subject files contain mostly printed matter and a few pieces of correspondence. These files are divided into two subseries: "Subject-Who's Who" and "Subject." Handwritten notes on many documents indicate that Helen kept files on (at least) people, legislation, nations, and organizations. She wrote "Who's Who" on materials relating to particular individuals. Only part of the index to her files remains. It appears that she divided the subjects into broad topics and then alphabetized them within each topic. According to the surviving index (Box 72N Folder 15), File #5 was "Patriotism and History," and File #3 was "Radicalism." Because it is impossible to reconstruct the entire filing system, the folder titles reflect either folders that remained from her file cabinets, or were created because Cummings labelled papers. For example, when Lloyd House received this collection there was not a folder labelled "Labor." One was created, however, because Helen wrote "Labor" at the top of a pamphlet.
The miscellaneous sections at the end of each subseries are a catch-all, not created by Helen. Because of the overlap of people with subjects, and subjects with other subjects, information in folders are not exclusive. For example, there is a "Who's Who" folder on Earl Browder, the Communist Party's candidate for president in 1936 and 1940. These is also a "Subject" folder on the Communist Party. Necessarily, these two overlap. The folders "Trials," "Citizenship," "Immigration," and "Constitution-U.S." contain articles about, or letters to newspaper editors, written by Helen. Several folders, particularly "Immigration," and "Subsidiary Movements," contain issues of "The Daily Data Sheet of the Key Men in America." The purpose of these appears to provide information about Communist and Socialist activities in the U.S. At least one clipping in the subject files was printed after Helen's death. This may have occurred because Esther Green continued to maintain these files.
The Personal/Family series contains genealogical information, as well as obituaries of Helen, Norris, William Cummings (Helen's grandfather), and various other relatives.
The oversize materials include a clip sheet from the National Patriotic Council and approximately a dozen posters in Russian. There are also a few anti-Communism and anti- Socialism posters.
The bound volumes include Helen's diaries from 1894 to 1929 (not a complete set), an account book, a letter book, a prayer book, and an autograph book.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into five series: Correspondence, Subject Files, Personal/Family, Oversize, and Bound Volumes. Also, at the end of the collection (Boxes 72V and 72W) are two boxes of unidentified photo plates.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Photos were transferred to the photograph collection. The photos from this collection and the Esther Green Collection are mixed. Also, papers relating to the Ricketts family are now in the Ricketts Collection.
Contents List
- Correspondence 1870-June 1902 (Box 72)
  - Correspondence 1870-1888 (Box-folder 72:1)
  - Correspondence 1890-1891 (Box-folder 72:2)
  - Correspondence 1892-1893 (Box-folder 72:3)
  - Correspondence 1894 (Box-folder 72:4)
  - Correspondence 1895-1896 (Box-folder 72:5)
  - Correspondence 1897-April 1898 (Box-folder 72:6)
  - Correspondence September-December 1898 (Box-folder 72:7)
  - Correspondence January-October 1899 (Box-folder 72:8)
  - Correspondence November-December 1899 (Box-folder 72:9)
  - Correspondence January-April 1900 (Box-folder 72:10)
  - Correspondence May-August 1900 (Box-folder 72:11)
  - Correspondence September-December 1900 (Box-folder 72:12)
  - Correspondence January-April 1901 (Box-folder 72:13)
  - Correspondence May-September 1901 (Box-folder 72:14)
  - Correspondence October 1901 (Box-folder 72:15)
  - Correspondence December 1901 (Box-folder 72:16)
  - Correspondence January-February 1902 (Box-folder 72:17)
  - Correspondence April-June 1902 (Box-folder 72:18)
- Correspondence July 1902-December 1905 (Box 72A)
  - Correspondence July-September 1902 (Box-folder 72A:1)
  - Correspodence October-November 1902 (Box-folder 72A:2)
  - Correspondence December 1902 (Box-folder 72A:3)
  - Correspondence January 1903 (Box-folder 72A:4)
  - Correspondence February-March 1903 (Box-folder 72A:5)
  - Correspondence April-May 1903 (Box-folder 72A:6)
  - Correspondence June -August 1903 (Box-folder 72A:7)
  - Correspondence October-December 1903 (Box-folder 72A:8)
  - Correspondence January-March 1904 (Box-folder 72A:9)
  - Correspondence April-May 1904 (Box-folder 72A:10)
  - Correspondence June-August 1904 (Box-folder 72A:11)
  - Correspondence September-December 1904 (Box-folder 72A:12)
  - Correspondence January-June 1905 (Box-folder 72A:13)
  - Correspondence July-December 1905 (Box-folder 72A:14)
- Correspondence January 1906-1916 (Box 72B)
  - Correspondence January-April 1906 (Box-folder 72B:1)
  - Correspondence May-December 1906 (Box-folder 72B:2)
  - Correspondence 1907 (Box-folder 72B:3)
  - Correspondence 1908 (Box-folder 72B:4)
  - Correspondence February-July 1909 (Box-folder 72B:5)
  - Correspondence August 1909 (Box-folder 72B:6)
  - Correspondence March-May 1910 (Box-folder 72B:7)
  - Correspondence June-December 1910 (Box-folder 72B:8)
  - Correspondence February-July 1911 (Box-folder 72B:9)
  - Correspondence August 1911-1912 (Box-folder 72B:10)
  - Correspondence 1914-1915 (Box-folder 72B:11)
  - Correspondence 1916 (Box-folder 72B:12)
- Correspondence January 1917-December 1927 (Box 72C)
  - Correspondence January-April 1917 (Box-folder 72C:1)
  - Correspondence May-December 1917 (Box-folder 72C:2)
  - Correspondence 1918 (Box-folder 72C:3)
  - Correspondence January-April 1919 (Box-folder 72C:4)
  - Correspondence June-December 1919 (Box-folder 72C:5)
  - Correspondence January-April 1920 (Box-folder 72C:6)
  - Correspondence May-August1920 (Box-folder 72C:7)
  - Correspondence September-November 1920 (Box-folder 72C:8)
  - Correspondence 1921-1924 (Box-folder 72C:9)
  - Correspondence 1925 (Box-folder 72C:10)
  - Correspondence April-June 1926 (Box-folder 72C:11)
  - Correspondence July-December 1926 (Box-folder 72C:12)
  - Correspondence January-June 1927 (Box-folder 72C:13)
  - Correspondence September-November 1927 (Box-folder 72C:14)
  - Correspondence December 1927 (Box-folder 72C:15)
- Correspondence January 1928-December 1933 (Box 72D)
  - Correspondence January-April 1928 (Box-folder 72D:1)
  - Correspondence May-December 1928 (Box-folder 72D:2)
  - Correspondence 1929 (Box-folder 72D:3)
  - Correspondence 1930 (Box-folder 72D:4)
  - Correspondence January-July 1931 (Box-folder 72D:5)
  - Correspondence August-October 1931 (Box-folder 72D:6)
  - Correspondence November-December 1931 (Box-folder 72D:7)
  - Correspondence January-May 1932 (Box-folder 72D:8)
  - Correspondence June-July 1932 (Box-folder 72D:9)
  - Correspondence August-December 1932 (Box-folder 72D:10)
  - Correspondence January-April 1933 (Box-folder 72D:11)
  - Correspondence May-July 1933 (Box-folder 72D:12)
  - Correspondence August-December 1933 (Box-folder 72D:13)
- Correspondence January 1934-December 1937 (Box 72E)
  - Correspondence January 1934 (Box-folder 72E:1)
  - Correspondence February-March 1934 (Box-folder 72E:2)
  - Correspondence April-November 1934 (Box-folder 72E:3)
  - Correspondence January-April 1935 (Box-folder 72E:4)
  - Correspondence May 1935 (Box-folder 72E:5)
  - Correspondence June 1935 (Box-folder 72E:6)
  - Correspondence July-August 1935 (Box-folder 72E:7)
  - Correspondence September-October 1935 (Box-folder 72E:8)
  - Correspondence November-December 1935 (Box-folder 72E:9)
  - Correspondence January-June 1936 (Box-folder 72E:10)
  - Correspondence August 1936 (Box-folder 72E:11)
  - Correspondence September 1936 (Box-folder 72E:12)
  - Correspondence October-December 1936 (Box-folder 72E:13)
  - Correspondence January-February 1937 (Box-folder 72E:14)
  - Correspondence March-April 1937 (Box-folder 72E:15)
  - Correspondence May 1937 (Box-folder 72E:16)
  - Correspondence June-July 1937 (Box-folder 72E:17)
  - Correspondence August-September 1937 (Box-folder 72E:18)
  - Correspondence October 1937 (Box-folder 72E:19)
  - Correspondence November-December 1937 (Box-folder 72E:20)
- Correspondence January 1938-1943, undated (Box 72F)
  - Correspondence January-February 1938 (Box-folder 72F:1)
  - Correspondence March 1938 (Box-folder 72F:2)
  - Correspondence April 1938 (Box-folder 72F:3)
  - Correspondence May-August 1938 (Box-folder 72F:4)
  - Correspondence September-November 1938 (Box-folder 72F:5)
  - Correspondence January-February 1939 (Box-folder 72F:6)
  - Correspondence March-April 1939 (Box-folder 72F:7)
  - Correspondence May 1939 (Box-folder 72F:8)
  - Correspondence June-August 1939 (Box-folder 72F:9)
  - Correspondence September-November 1939 (Box-folder 72F:10)
  - Correspondence April-May 1940 (Box-folder 72F:11)
  - Correspondence June 1940 (Box-folder 72F:12)
  - Correspondence June 1940 (Box-folder 72F:13)
  - Correspondence July 1940 (Box-folder 72F:14)
  - Correspondence August 1940-1941 (Box-folder 72F:15)
  - Correspondence 1942-1943 (Box-folder 72F:16)
  - Correspondence undated (Box-folder 72F:17)
  - Correspondence undated (Box-folder 72F:18)
- Subject Files-Who's Who: Jane Addams - Maxim Litinov (Box 72G)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Jane Addams (Box-folder 72G:1)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Roger N. Baldwin (Box-folder 72G:2)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who William H. Borah (Box-folder 72G:3)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Earl Browder (Box-folder 72G:4)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who S. Parkes Cadman (Box-folder 72G:5)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Carrie Chapman Catt (Box-folder 72G:6)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Clarence Darrow (Box-folder 72G:7)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Jesse Dell (Box-folder 72G:8)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who John Dewey (Box-folder 72G:9)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Sherwood Eddy (Box-folder 72G:10)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Albert Einstein (Box-folder 72G:11)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Harry E. Fosdick (Box-folder 72G:12)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Felix Frankfurter (Box-folder 72G:13)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Elizabeth Gilman (Box-folder 72G:14)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Carter Glass (Box-folder 72G:15)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Emma Goldman (Box-folder 72G:16)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who William Green (Box-folder 72G:17)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who E. Julius Haldeman (Box-folder 72G:18)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Norman Hapgood (Box-folder 72G:19)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Carlton J.H. Hayes (Box-folder 72G:20)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Carlton J.H. Hayes (Box-folder 72G:21)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who William R. Hearst (Box-folder 72G:22)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Patrick Henry (Box-folder 72G:23)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Stanley High (Box-folder 72G:24)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Adolf Hitler (Box-folder 72G:25)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who John Haynes Holmes (Box-folder 72G:26)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Leta S. Hollingsworth (Box-folder 72G:27)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Herbert Hoover (Box-folder 72G:28)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Rupert Hughes (Box-folder 72G:29)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Cordell/William Hull (Box-folder 72G:30)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Inez Haynes Irwin (Box-folder 72G:31)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Rufus M. Jones (Box-folder 72G:32)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Michael Karolyi (Box-folder 72G:33)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Paul F. Kassay (Box-folder 72G:34)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Florence Kelley (Box-folder 72G:35)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Alexander Kollentay (Box-folder 72G:36)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Vladimir Lenin (Box-folder 72G:37)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Frederick J. Libby (Box-folder 72G:38)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Maxim Litinov (Box-folder 72G:39)
- Subject Files: Who's Who Broadus Mitchell - American Negro Labor Congress (Box 72H)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Broadus Mitchell (Box-folder 72H:1)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Tom Mooney (Box-folder 72H:2)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Scott Nearing (Box-folder 72H:3)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Ben Newman (Box-folder 72H:4)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who George W. Norris (Box-folder 72H:5)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Eugene O'Neill (Box-folder 72H:6)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Kirby Page (Box-folder 72H:7)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Maude Wood Park (Box-folder 72H:8)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Frances Perkins (Box-folder 72H:9)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who John Reed (Box-folder 72H:10)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Maude Royden (Box-folder 72H:11)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Eleanor Roosevelt (Box-folder 72H:12)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Franklin D. Roosevelt (Box-folder 72H:13)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Franklin D. Roosevelt (Box-folder 72H:14)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Bertrand Russell (Box-folder 72H:15)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Charles E. Ruthenberg (Box-folder 72H:16)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who John Sayre (Box-folder 72H:17)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Rose Schneidermann (Box-folder 72H:18)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Rosika Schwimmer (Box-folder 72H:19)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Al Smith (Box-folder 72H:20)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Charles H. Smith (Box-folder 72H:21)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Anna Louise Strong (Box-folder 72H:22)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Norman Thomas (Box-folder 72H:23)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who William Allen White (Box-folder 72H:24)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who Charles A. Whitney (Box-folder 72H:25)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who A-B misc. (Box-folder 72H:26)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who D-H misc. (Box-folder 72H:27)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who I-M misc. (Box-folder 72H:28)
  - Subject Files-Who's Who N-W misc. (Box-folder 72H:29)
  - Subject Files-American Alliance of the U.S. (Box-folder 72H:30)
  - Subject Files-American Arbitration Association (Box-folder 72H:31)
  - Subject Files-American Defense Society (Box-folder 72H:32)
  - Subject Files-American Federation of Teachers (Box-folder 72H:33)
  - Subject Files-American League Against War and Fascism (Box-folder 72H:34)
  - Subject Files-American Legion (Box-folder 72H:35)
  - Subject Files-American Negro Labor Congress (Box-folder 72H:36)
- Subject Files: American Political Prisoners League - China (Box 72I)
  - Subject Files-American Political Prisoners League (Box-folder 72I:1)
  - Subject Files-American Vigilant Intelligence Federation (Box-folder 72I:2)
  - Subject Files-Americanization (Box-folder 72I:3)
  - Subject Files-Anti-Patriotic Activities (Box-folder 72I:4)
  - Subject Files-Arabia (Box-folder 72I:5)
  - Subject Files-Archaeology (Box-folder 72I:6)
  - Subject Files-Armistice (Box-folder 72I:7)
  - Subject Files-Army (Box-folder 72I:8)
  - Subject Files-Art and Literature (Box-folder 72I:9)
  - Subject Files-Atheism (Box-folder 72I:10)
  - Subject Files-Atheism (Box-folder 72I:11)
  - Subject Files-Atheism (Box-folder 72I:12)
  - Subject Files-Aviation (Box-folder 72I:13)
  - Subject Files-Banks and Banking, radicalism in (Box-folder 72I:14)
  - Subject Files-Battles (Box-folder 72I:15)
  - Subject Files-Belgium (Box-folder 72I:16)
  - Subject Files-Better American Federation (Box-folder 72I:17)
  - Subject Files-Bible Historical Places (Box-folder 72I:18)
  - Subject Files-Birth Control (Box-folder 72I:19)
  - Subject Files-Bolshevism (Box-folder 72I:20)
  - Subject Files-Bonus (Box-folder 72I:21)
  - Subject Files-Book Reviews (Box-folder 72I:22)
  - Subject Files-Books (Box-folder 72I:23)
  - Subject Files-British Policies (Box-folder 72I:24)
  - Subject Files-Business and Women's Professional Clubs (Box-folder 72I:25)
  - Subject Files-Bureaucracy (Box-folder 72I:26)
  - Subject Files-Calendar Simplification (Box-folder 72I:27)
  - Subject Files-Campaign Literature (Box-folder 72I:28)
  - Subject Files-Celebrations and Anniversaries, including 100th Anniversary of George Washington's Death (Box-folder 72I:29)
  - Subject Files-Celebrations and Anniversaries-Philadelphia Sesquicentennial International Exposition (Box-folder 72I:30)
  - Subject Files-China (Box-folder 72I:31)
- Subject Files: Christ Church - Federal Council of the Churches (Box 72J)
  - Subject Files-Christ Church (Box-folder 72J:1)
  - Subject Files-Christ Church (Box-folder 72J:2)
  - Subject Files-Citizenship, American (Box-folder 72J:3)
  - Subject Files-Colonial Dames (Box-folder 72J:4)
  - Subject Files-Communist Party (Box-folder 72J:5)
  - Subject Files-Congress (Box-folder 72J:6)
  - Subject Files-Conservation (Box-folder 72J:7)
  - Subject Files-Constitution, U.S. (Box-folder 72J:8)
  - Subject Files-Constitution, U.S. (Box-folder 72J:9)
  - Subject Files-Creed, America's (Box-folder 72J:10)
  - Subject Files-Crime (Box-folder 72J:11)
  - Subject Files-D.A.R.[Daughters of the American Revolution] (Box-folder 72J:12)
  - Subject Files-D.A.R.[Daughters of the American Revolution] (Box-folder 72J:13)
  - Subject Files-D.A.R.[Daughters of the American Revolution] (Box-folder 72J:14)
  - Subject Files-Declaration of Independence (Box-folder 72J:15)
  - Subject Files-England (Box-folder 72J:16)
  - Subject Files-Expeditions of National Importance (Box-folder 72J:17)
  - Subject Files-Federal Council of the Churches (Box-folder 72J:18)
- Subject Files: Flag, U.S. - I.W.W. [Industrial Workers] (Box 72K)
  - Subject Files-Flag, U.S. (Box-folder 72K:1)
  - Subject Files-Flag, U.S. (Box-folder 72K:2)
  - Subject Files-Foreign Policy Association (Box-folder 72K:3)
  - Subject Files-Fourth of July (Box-folder 72K:4)
  - Subject Files-France (Box-folder 72K:5)
  - Subject Files-Gadsby's Tavern (Box-folder 72J:6)
  - Subject Files-Gold (Box-folder 72K:7)
  - Subject Files-Greece (Box-folder 72K:8)
  - Subject Files-Haiti (Box-folder 72K:9)
  - Subject Files-Heller Bill (Box-folder 72K:10)
  - Subject Files-Historic Places and Events (Box-folder 72K:11)
  - Subject Files-Holland (Box-folder 72K:12)
  - Subject Files-Honduras (Box-folder 72K:13)
  - Subject Files-Immigration (Box-folder 72K:14)
  - Subject Files-Immigration (Box-folder 72K:15)
  - Subject Files-Immigration (Box-folder 72K:16)
  - Subject Files-Immigration (Box-folder 72K:17)
  - Subject Files-Immigration (Box-folder 72K:18)
  - Subject Files-Immigration (Box-folder 72K:19)
- Subject Files: India - Social Security (Box 72L)
  - Subject Files-India (Box-folder 72L:1)
  - Subject Files-I.W.W. [Industrial Workers of the World] (Box-folder 72L:2)
  - Subject Files-Industry (Box-folder 72L:3)
  - Subject Files-Industry (Box-folder 72L:4)
  - Subject Files-Institute of International Education (Box-folder 72L:5)
  - Subject Files-Interlocking Directories (Box-folder 72L:6)
  - Subject Files-International Relations (Box-folder 72L:7)
  - Subject Files-Ireland (Box-folder 72L:8)
  - Subject Files-Italy (Box-folder 72L:9)
  - Subject Files-Japan, radicalism in (Box-folder 72L:10)
  - Subject Files-Jews (Box-folder 72L:11)
  - Subject Files-Jews (Box-folder 72L:12)
  - Subject Files-Jugoslavia (Box-folder 72L:13)
  - Subject Files-Kellogg Treaty or Peace Pact (Box-folder 72L:14)
  - Subject Files-Labor (Box-folder 72L:15)
  - Subject Files-League for Industrial Democracy (Box-folder 72L:16)
  - Subject Files-Marriage and Divorce (Box-folder 72L:17)
  - Subject Files-National Defense (Box-folder 72L:18)
  - Subject Files-Negroes (Box-folder 72L:19)
  - Subject Files-Peace (Box-folder 72L:20)
  - Subject Files-Sabotage, acts of (Box-folder 72K:21)
  - Subject Files-Sacco and Vanzetti (Box-folder 72L:22)
  - Subject Files-Wetha L. Sanford Alumnae Assoc. (Box-folder 72L:23)
  - Subject Files-Save Our Schools Committee (Box-folder 72L:24)
  - Subject Files-Science League of America (Box-folder 72L:25)
  - Subject Files-Sex (Box-folder 72L:26)
  - Subject Files-Siam (Box-folder 72L:27)
  - Subject Files-Slacker's Oath (Box-folder 72L:28)
  - Subject Files-Slogans (Box-folder 72L:29)
  - Subject Files-Slums (Box-folder 72L:30)
  - Subject Files-Social Security (Box-folder 72L:31)
- Subject Files: Socialism - Women's Peace Party (Box 72M)
  - Subject Files-Socialism (Box-folder 72M:1)
  - Subject Files-South America, radicalism in (Box-folder 72M:2)
  - Subject Files-Spain (Box-folder 72M:3)
  - Subject Files-Spy System (Box-folder 72M:4)
  - Subject Files-Strikes (Box-folder 72M:5)
  - Subject Files-Students International Union (Box-folder 72M:6)
  - Subject Files-Subsidiary Movements (Box-folder 72M:7)
  - Subject Files-Supreme Court (Box-folder 72M:8)
  - Subject Files-Sweden (Box-folder 72M:9)
  - Subject Files-Syndicalism (Box-folder 72M:10)
  - Subject Files-Tariff (Box-folder 72M:11)
  - Subject Files-Taxes (Box-folder 72M:12)
  - Subject Files-Theatres, radicalism in (Box-folder 72M:13)
  - Subject Files-Third Party (Box-folder 72M:14)
  - Subject Files-Tours (Box-folder 72M:15)
  - Subject Files-Townsend (Box-folder 72M:16)
  - Subject Files-Trade-foreign (Box-folder 72M:17)
  - Subject Files-Trade Union League (Box-folder 72M:18)
  - Subject Files-Trials (Box-folder 72M:19)
  - Subject Files-Trusts (Box-folder 72M:20)
  - Subject Files-Turkey (Box-folder 72M:21)
  - Subject Files-U.S. in Competition with Foreign Business (Box-folder 72M:22)
  - Subject Files-Unemployed (Box-folder 72M:23)
  - Subject Files-Unions [Company] (Box-folder 72M:24)
  - Subject Files-United Mine Workers (Box-folder 72M:25)
  - Subject Files-United States Flag Assoc. (Box-folder 72M:26)
  - Subject Files-Utopian Society (Box-folder 72M:27)
  - Subject Files-Veterans (Box-folder 72M:28)
  - Subject Files-Vigilante (Box-folder 72M:29)
  - Subject Files-Violence (Box-folder 72M:30)
  - Subject Files-War (Box-folder 72M:31)
  - Subject Files-War Resisters' League (Box-folder 72M:32)
  - Subject Files-Washington Club (Box-folder 72M:33)
  - Subject Files-Waterways (Box-folder 72M:34)
  - Subject Files-Workers' International Defense League (Box-folder 72M:35)
  - Subject Files-Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (Box-folder 72M:36)
  - Subject Files-Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (Box-folder 72M:37)
  - Subject Files-Women's Lobby (Box-folder 72M:38)
  - Subject Files-Women's Peace Party (Box-folder 72M:39)